Finding Aid for Harry Burns Hutchins papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Visual Material
  - Prints (Box 22)
Carhart, 10-19, 11/17/15; 10-20. 11/22/15
Murfin, 10-16, 10/25 & 10/28/15
Scherer, 10-16, 10/26/15; 10-19, 11/17/15
Turner, 10-16, 10/28/15; 10-19, 11/17/15
Willett, 10-16, 10/28/15, R10-17, 11/4/15; 10-20, 11/22/15
Women's physical education
Bigelow, 3-26, 12/14/11
Faculty freedom of speech issue
Bohn, 1-24, 1/6/10 (re: his speech on socialism)
Cooley, 1-22, 12/14 & 12/15/09
Fowler, 1-31, 4/18/10
Latham, 1-22, 12/3/09
Sawyer, 1-30, 4/9/10
Spalding, 1-22, 12/13 & 12/14/09
Financing of the University
General
Ferris, 5-29, 2/4 & 2/6/13
Hopkins, 8-13, 10/1 & 10/5/14
Hubbard, 5-29, 2/4 & 2/6/13
Osborne, 5-20, 11/24/12
Mill tax legislation
King, 2-35, 5/1 & 5/5/11
Slauson, 4-21, 6/1/12
Private donations and funding
Wright, 2-25, 2/16/11
State granting of cutover land to U-M
McEldownery, 3-11, 7/24/11
Fraternities and sororities
Collins, 7-18, 5/11/14, R7-19, 5/28/14; 8-16, 10/13/14, R8-18,11/13/14
Cooley, 7-18, 5/8 & 5/9/14
Jordan, 7-15, 4/21/14
Levere, 7-24, 6/26/14
Inquiries from other educational institutions
(Note: By 1913-14 the number of inquiries was decreasing and most inquiries were referred to various other university officials. Thus there was no record of replies. Indexing of inquiries does not continue after Box 7.)
General
Bovard, 2-35, 5/2/11, R5/4/11 (sent to Ward)
Brewer, 7-10, 3/14/14, R7-11, 3/18/14
Chamberlin, 7-16, 4/25 & 4/27/14 (admissions qualifications)
Clark, 7-16, 4/28/14, R7-17, 5/14/14 (academic ranking for administrators)
Comstock, 5-16, 10/23 & 10/28/12 (use of academic costume)
Curtiss, 5-26, 1/14/13, R5-29, 2/5/13 (outside work of scientists, control of patents)
Harmon, 1-33, 5/16/10, R5/26/10; 3-8, 7/5/11, R3-9, 7/10/11
Hart, 6-21, 10/16/13, R6-22, 10/25/13
Hetzel, 3-16, 9/27/11
McMurricks, 4-3, 1/18/12, R4-4, 1/22/12
Potts, 5-33, 3/5/13; R5-34, 3/8 & 3/13/13 (combining all state colleges in one system)
Smith, 5-19, 11/18/12, R5-20, 11/25/12
Strong, 6-18, 9/20 & 9/24/13
Templin, 4-7, 2/17/12, R4-8, 2/24/12
Walthall, 5-14, 10/9 & 10/14/12
Williston, 1-33, 5/31/10
Alumni organization
Benson, 4-13, 4/1/12, R4/4/23
Bralley, 7-11, 3/20/14, R7-12, 3/23/14
Stanton, 6-8, 5/27 & 5/30/13
Athletics
Garrett, 7-1, 1/1 & 1/4/14
Kingsbury, 6-29, 12/12/13, R6-30, 12/22/13; 7-7, 2/17 & 2/24/14
Combined courses with Albion College in law and medicine
Barr, 7-7, 2/18/14, R 7-9,3/5/14
Dickie, 7-6, 2/10/& 2/11/14
Curriculum
Gilvray, 2-34, 4/26/11
Hallam, 4-3, 1/16/12, R4-4, 1/24/12
Jewett, 1-33, 5/20 & 5/27/10
Faculty matters
Angell, 4-11, 3/16/12, R4-13, 4/4/12(teaching hours required); 5-22,12/10 & 12/12/12 (qualifications for title of professor)
Appell, 7-13, 4/6/14, R7-14, 4/14/14
Brindley, 7-10, 3/9 & 3/11/14
Cary, 4-19, 5/21/12, R4-20, 5/29/12 (use of teaching assistants)
Eigenmann, 6-8, 5/28 & 5/30/13 (comparative salaries)
Fulmer, 5-25, 1/3/11, R5-26, 1/13/13 (sabbatical leaves)
Hawkins, 6-20, 10/13 & 10/16/13 (sabbatical leaves)
Johnston, 4-13, 4/2/12, R4/5/12
Landes, 7-22, 6/13/14, R8-2, 7/9/14 (salaries and promotions)
McCaffrey, 1-32, 5/6 & 5/7/10 (faculty organization)
McPherson, 4-6, 2/14/12, R4-8, 2/24/12 (faculty research required)
Tobey, 3-11, 7/25 & 7/27/11 (hours of teaching required)
Final examination policy
Ketchum, 2-27, 3/1 & 3/7/11
McCaskey, 2-27, 3/1 & 3/3/11
Financing
Bates, 7-12, 3/23 & 3/26/14
Benton, 5-20, 11/21 & 11/25/12
Henderson, 3-21, 11/4/10 (general financing)
Kingsbury, 5-16, 10/30/12, R5-17, 11/4/12
Mackey, 3-21, 11/4/11; 3-27, 12/20/11, R3-28, 12/28/11 (fees for student activities)
Powell, 2-1d, 8/6/10
Prescott, 5-14, 10/18/12 (millage tax)
Puryear, 1-33, 5/17/10, R5/26/10 (millage tax & state support)
Reynolds, 1-23, 12/16 & 12/21/09; 5-14, 10/8 10/10/12 (taxing plans)
Strong, 5-16, 10/28 & 10/31/12
Fraternities and sororities
Baer, 6-25, 11/19 & 11/21/13 (re: attitudes toward Jews)
Baum, 7-18, 5/8 & 5/11/14
Boyd, 5-1, 7/3/12, R5-2, 7/8/12
Collins, 8-16, 10/13/14, R8-18, 11/13/14
Kingsbury, 7-13, 4/6/14/, R7-14, 4/10/14
Lloyd, 3-2, 5/19/11, R5/22/11
Potts, 5-26, 1/13/13, R5-27, 1/19/13
Robitshek, 5-18, 11/12 & 11/14/12
Governance of the university
Baker, 5-18, 11/9 & 11/14/12
Coffey, 7-13, 4/14/14, R7-14, 4/10/14
Filbey, 6-21, 10/17/13, R6-22, 10/24/13
Fuller, 7-5, 2/6 & 2/11/14
Hall, 5-32, 2/24/13
Mason, 7-21, 6/3 & 6/6/14
Mattson, 7-6, 2/9 & 2/13/14
Schurmann, 7-18, 5/13/14, R7-19, 5/18/14
Womack, 5-16, 10/24 & 10/28/12
Physical education organization
Cooke, 4-1, 1/7/12, R4-2, 1/11/12
Religious education
Davis,5-24, 12/22 & 12/26/12
Edwards. 5-22, 12/13 & 12/18/12
Stone, 5-36, 3/24 & 3/27/13
Wicker, 5-16, 10/24 & 10/28/12
Services to state of Michigan
Ferris, 5-24, 12/29/12
Gillette, 4-13, 4/4/12
Henderson, 5-24, 12/30/12
Ripley, 1-30, 4/8 & 4/13/10
Schafer, 4-11, 3/19/11
Smith, 5-18, 11/13/12
Student housing
Detrick, 3-17, 10/5/11, (private rooms vs. fraternity living)
Littlejohn, 5-4, 7/26 & 7/30/12 (women's building)
Norris, 4-2, 1/8/12 (dormitories)
Schuman, 3-25, 12/5/11, R12/7/11; 3-26, 12/11/11 (boarding house inspection)
Student life
Cavanaugh, 4-4, 1/31/12, R4-5, 2/6/12 (rules for closing times for parties, dances)
Gladson, 1/32, 5/4 & 5/7/10 (student government organization)
Hostetter, 7-13, 4/1/14, R7-14, 4/10/14
Miller, 7-23, 6-18/14, R8-1, 7/2/14 (student government)
Sabine, 4-6, 2/14/12, R4-9, 3/2/12 (vocational guidance)
Samson, 5-6, 8/14/12, R5-7, 8/19/12 (control of students in dorms)
Warman, 7-16, 4/22/14, R7-17, 5/1/14 (student government)
End of Indexing of inquiries from other institutions. This indexing does not continue after Box 7.
Military preparedness
General
Adams, 10-18, 11/11/15, R10-19, 11/15/15
Arneill, 10-3, 7/19/15
Beadle, 10-18, 11/9/15, R10-19, 11/16/15
Benton, 7-12, 3/31/14, R7-13, 4/9/14
DeNancrede, 9-17, 5/7/15
Geisler, 9-23, 6/15 & 6/18-15
Gimperling, 10-3, 7/16/15
Hobbs, 10-19, 11/15, 16, & 20/15
Humphrey, 10-21, 12/1 & 12/6/15
Kuss, 10-21, 12/1/15
MacCracken, 9-10, 3/10/15
Raycroft, 8-17,11/6/14, R8-18, 11/13/14
Smith, 10-21, 12/4 & 12/6/15
Stockton, 9-22, 6/12/15; 10-1, 7/1/15
Thompson, 10-16, 10/29/15, R10-17, 11/2/15
Van Anda, 9-2, 1/13/15, R9-3, 1/15/15
White, 10-21, 12/4 & 12/7/15
Williams, 9-8, 2/25 & 2/26/15
Wolfenden, 7-15, 4/18 & 4/21/14
Summer training camps
Drinker, 10-6, 8/13/15; 10-16, 10/26/15; 10-19, 11/20/15, R10-21, 12/6/15
Military Training Camp, 10-2, 7/9/15
Wood, 8-2, 7/10/14, 10-2, 7/12 & 7/13/15; 10-3, 7/16/15; 10-6, 8/4/15, R10-7,8/19/15
Non-resident students
Grant, 2-21, 1/30/11, R2/22, 2/1/11
Scott, 2-21, 1-30-11
"Outside work" by faculty
Boughton, 2-31, 4/3/11, R4/5/11
Cooley, 4-19, 5/24/12 in response to Merrill, 4-19, 5/10/12; HBH reply 4/19, 5/27/12; 9-23, 6/16/15
Relations with other state universities
Clements, 5-32, 2/27/13 (2 letters)
Craighead, 5-27, 1/15/13
Haddock, 4-4, 1/27/12
Ladd, 5-8, 8/26/12, R5-12, 9/26/12
McKenny, 5-29, 2/4 & 2/6/13; 6-26, 11/28/13, R6-27, 12/2/13; 6-29, 12/16/13
McNair, 5-5, 8/3/12, R5-12, 9/24/12; 5-13, 10/4/12
McVey,5-27, 1/16/13, R5-29, 2/5/13; 6-8, 5/23 & 5/26/13
Wright, 5-23, 12/17 & 12/18/12
Services to the state of Michigan
Barnes, 8-24, 12/22 & 12/24/14
Ferris, 9-1, 1/2/15
Labadie, 7-18, 5/13/14
Riggs, 9-11, 3/19/14
Student discipline
General
Bates, 8-24, 12/30/14
Berry, 1-29, 3/21/10, 3/24/10
Burke, 6-21, 10/16 & 10/17/13; 8-24, 12/30 & 12/31/14
Clark, 2-33, 4/20/11, R2-34, 4/29/11
Cooley, 2-6, 10/18, 10/19, & 10/21/10; 3-17, 10/3/11
Cornwell, 4-14, 4/8 & 4/9/12; 4-15, 4/16/12; 4-16, 4/25/12
Cross, 6-4, 4/29/13, R6-5, 5/2/13
Giddings, 1-31, 4/22/10
Gorman, 2-5, 10/13/10; 2-6, 10/17/10; 2-7, 10/24/10
Griffiths, 1-23, 12/27 & 12/30/09 (re:Berry)
Holmes, 8-19, 11/18 & 11/19/14
Kelley, 1-19, 10/25/09 (re:hazing); 10/28/09; 1-20, 11/9/09; 2-1c, 7/27 & 7/30/10
Koehler, 1-29, 3/17/10, 3/23 & 3/25/10
McKenny, 7-11, 3/17 & 3/19/14
Pomper, 8-4, 7/30 & 7/31/14, R8-5, 8/1/14
Strong, 10-22, 12/10 & 12/13/15
Toms, 1-28, 3/15/10, R3/16/10
Webster, 1-28, 3/14/10
Samuel Shulkin case
Laughlin, 10-24, 12/28 & 12/30/15
Northwestern Medical School, 10-23, 12/15/15
Shulkin, 10-13, 10/5/15, R10-16, 10/28/15; 10-19, 11/18/15; 10-20, 11/8 & 11/26/15; 10-21, 12/2 & 12/6/15; 10-22, 12/9, 12/12 & 12/14/15
Suspension of Michael Foote
Bates, 5-18, 11/9 & 11/12/12
Brown, 5-18, 11/11 & 11/14/12
Burke, 5-18, 11/11 & 11/14/12
Effinger, 5-18, 11/9/12
Marks, 5-22, 12/14 & 12/18/12
Reed, 6-13, 7/3 & 7/5/13; 6-21, 10/21 & 10/23/13
Student health
General
Marks, 5-11, 9/20/12
Rathbone, 3-2, 5/18/11, R5/20/11
Shumway, 2-9, 11/15/10
Vaughan, 5-11, 9/20/12
Smallpox outbreaks
Atwater, 2-9, 11/12/10, 11/14/10
Bates, 3-1, 5/11/11
Beebe, 9-1, 1/12/15
Cummings, 9-1, 1/12/15
Clements, 2-9, 11/12, 11/14, & 11/15/10
Smith, 2-34, 4/24/11
Wessinger, 9-1, 1/10 & 1/12/15
Undergraduate work, re-organization of
Butts, 4-4, 1/24/12
Women in the university
General
Baumgardner, 8-21, 12/7/14, R8-22, 12/10/14
Jordan, 10-4, 7/28/15
Palmer, 7-19, 5/20/14, R7-20, 5/29/14
Faculty
Salmon, 3-22, 11/15/11, referred to Van Tyne, his reply, 3-23, 11/23/11; HBH reply, 11/25/11
Students (co-education)
Bok, 2-13, 12/12/10, R12/15/10
Guyot, 2-4, 1/28/11; 2-18, 1/14/11; 2-21, 1/28/11
Judkins, 1-24, 1/12/10
Kirchwey, 1-22, 12/1 & 12/13/09 (effect of women attending law school with men students)
Women's education
Douglass, 5-27, 1/17/13; R5-28, 1/23/13
Hopwood, 9-20, 5/22/15, R9-21, 6/4/15
Hutchinson, 6-29, 12/15/13, R6-27, 12/30/13
Miller, 7-11, 3/17 & 3/19/14
Porter, 7-8, 2/28/14, R 7-9, 3/3/14
Salmon, 10-15, 10/19/15, R10-16, 10/23/15
World War I related matters
Bates, 10-20, 11/29/15 (re: anti-English propaganda by Indian students)
Bulkley, 10-21, 12/3,9,& 13/15, R10-22, 12/9 & 12/13/15 (re: German propaganda by Prof. Hobbs)
Bullen, 10-17, 11/5/15
Dunlap, 8-20, 11/23/14
Ferris, 10-5, 8/4 & 8/5/15
Hall 8-12, 9/27 & 9/29/14 (Red Cross fund-raising
Haselden, 10-20,11/22/15
Henry, 10-22, 12/14/15
Hobbs, 10-19, 11/15 & 11/16/15
Marsh, 9-11, 3/20/15, R9-12, 3/23/15
Miller 8-12, 9/25 & 9/28/14
Sanders, 10-16, 10/25/15, R10-19, 11/16/15 (effect of war on American Academy in Rome)
Sarton, 10-17, 11/2 (2 letters) & 11/4/15
Sullivan, 10-20, 11/26/15, R10-21, 12/6/15 (re: remarks of Hobbs) 9/28/14
II. Building Program
General
Babst, 3-9, 7/14, 7/20 & 7/21/11; 3-11, 7/28/11;7-12, 3/23 & 3/25/14
Brooks, 8-16, 10-24/14 (land acquisition)
Clements, 1-24, 1/14/10; 2-1a, 7/11/10, R7/12/10 (use of library building); 2-1f, 9/5/10; 2-29, 3/18 & 3/20/11; 2/31, 4/7/11, R2-32, 4/8/11; 2-31, 4/10/11; 3-9, 7/11, 7/13, & 7/14/11; 3-20, 10/28/11; 3-28, 12/27/11
Cook, 6-7, 5/19/13
Curtis, 3-26, 12/11/11
Fletcher, 2-28, 3/15/11; 2-29, 3/18 & 3/20/11, R3/23/11; 2-31,4/7/11; 3-1, 5/11/11
Haff, 3-13, 8/30/11, R3-6, 9/26/11
Kelsey, 7-15, 4/16 & 4/20/14
New York Alumni, 6-21, 10/16/13 (review of new buildings added)
Reed, 6-7, 5/19/13; 6-10, 6/11/13
Sawyer, 3-15, 9/16/11, R9/19/11
Travis, 5-23, 12/21/12
Demonstration school
Grant, 9-7, 2/17 & 2/20/15
Planck, 9-7, 2/17 & 2/20/25
Whitney, 9-5, 2/2/15
Hill Auditorium
Clements, 2-6, 10/18/10; 2-9, 11/11 & 11/14/10; 2-10, 11/21/10; 2-11, 11/28/10; 2-13, 2/14/10; 4-1, 1/3 & 1/4/12, R4-2, 1/8/12; 5-22, 12/10 & 12/11/12; 5-32, 2/24 & 2/25/13 7/18, 5/14/15, R7-19, 5/19/14
Ferris, 5-34, 3/12 & 3/14/13
Kahn, 6-14, 7/15/13
Kelsey, 2-9, 11/14/10
Stark, 5-34, 3/12/14; 6-1, 4/3 & 4/4/13; 6-3, 4/16/13
Townsend, 5-34, 3/12/13, R5-35, 3/15/13
Library
Bursley, 9-16, 4/26/15
Clements, 8-19, 11/19 & 11/20/14; 9-4, 1/29/15, R9-5, 2/1/15; 9-6, 4/30/15; 9-20, 5/26 & 5/28/15; 9-23, 6/15, 16, & 18/15; 9-24, 6/28 & 6/30/15; 10-1, 7/1 & 7/6/15; 10-9, 9/4 & 9/7/15; 10-11, 9/16/15; 10-13, 10/4, & 10/6/15
Edmunds, 10-2, 7/13/15
Gore, 9-14, 4/14/15
Kahn, 10-7, 8/16/15
Koch, 9-6, 2/12/15; 9-13, 4/5 & 4/6/15
Thompson, 10-2, 7/8/15
Michigan Union, Fund-raising and plans for
Bates, 10-21, 12/7 & 12/9/15; 10-22, 12/9, 11, & 13/15
Boynton, 10-4, 7/29/15
Cochran, 10-23, 12/18/15, R10-24, 12/27/15
Cutcheon, 10-17, 11/3/15
Durant, 10-14, 10/11/15, R10-16, 10/24/15; 10-22, 12/9, 11, & 13/15
Engineering News, 10-4, 7/29 & 7/31/15
Farrell, 10-14, 10/8 & 10/9/15; 10-18, 11/13 & 11/15/15
Fox, 10-22, 12/9/15
Gillette, 10-12, 9/27 & 9/29/15
Heath, 8-5, 8/4/14; 9-24, 6/25/15; 10-23, 12/21/15; 10-24, 12/30/15
Hughes, 10-7, 8/21 & 8/23/15; 10-8, 8/24 & 8/25/15; 10-11, 9/15/15
Junell, 10-12, 9/28/15, R10-13, 10/5/15
Killilea, 10-16, 10/24/15; 10-22, 12/9/15
Kleinstueck, 10-14, 10/9/15
Lee, 10-22, 12/9/15
Lightner, 10-16, 10/28/15 (2 letters)
McAndrew, 10-12, 9/30/15, R10-13, 10/4/15
McGraw, 10-15, 10/18/15, R10-16, 10/24/15; 10-17, 11/1,3,& 5/15; 10-20, 11/23/15
McKenzie, 10-21, 12/1 & 12/7/15
Maxwell, 10-15, 10/19/15
Pond, 10-18, 11/8/15
Reed, 10-20, 11/22/15
Richmond, 10-12, 9/27/15
Ripley, 10-4, 7/26/15
Rose, 10-17, 11/4/15; 10-18, 11/11/15, R10-19, 11/16/15
Tinsman, 10-16, 10/23/15 (list of Chicago area contributors)
Tweedy, 10-22, 12/9/15
Wilkinson, 10-22, 12/9 & 12/13/15; 10-23, 12/16 & 12/20/15
Wollman, 10-17, 11/4/15
Young, 10-5, 8/4 & 8/5/15
Olmsted plan for the campus
Clements, 9-21, 6/5, 7, & 6/10/15
Olmsted, 9-24, 6/23, 25, & 29/15
Shepard, 9-23, 6/16/15
Tealdi, 9-24, 6/30/15
Power Plant
Beal 4-19, 5/16/12
Clements, 2-11, 11/29 & 11/30/10; 2-17, 2/2/11 (2 letters); 2-21, 1/28/11; 2-26, 2/25/11, R2-27, 3/3/11; 2-27, 3/6/11; 4-2, 1/8/12; 4-9, 3/7/12; 4-10, 3/9/12; 4-12, 3/28/12; 4-20, 5/29 & 5/31/12; 4-22, 6/13 & 6/14/12; 4-23, 6/19/12; 5-17, 11/1 & 11/4/12; 5-22, 12/9/12; 5-32, 2/26/13 7-2, 1/10/14; 7-3, 1/15 & 1/16/14
Cooley, 4-1, 1/4/12
Hinchman, 9-3, 1/15/15
Hussey, 4-1, 1/2/12; 5-6, 8/14/12, R5-12, 9/24/12; 5-13, 10/7/12; 5-29, 2/6/13; 5-35, 3/20/13; 8-23, 12/18/14
Lamont, 4-12, 3/27/12, R4-13, 4/1/12; 5-18, 11/8/12
Nygren, Tenney & Ohmer, 5-11, 9//19/12
Sawyer, 8-23, 12/19/14
Residence Halls for Women
Note: Includes correspondence related to fund-raising efforts by alumnae, and the building of Newberry Hall and Martha Cook by private donation.
Clements, 6-10, 6/11/13; 6-11, 6-17-13, R6-12, 6/27/13
Cook, 2-24, 2/10/11 (2 letters); 2-27, 3/3/11; 3-4, 6/1 & 6/5/11, R3-4, 5/6/11; 5-4, 7/30/12; 5-33, 3/6/13; 6-7, 5/17/13; 6-12, 6/30/13; 10-12, 9/29/15; 10-13, 10/4/15 (2 letters)
Dewey, 2-8, 11/5/10, R11/8/10; 2-9, 11/12/10; 2-21, 1/28 & 1/30/11
Doan, 7-2, 1/8 & 1/10/14
Ferris, 10-12, 9/30/15; 10-14, 10/9 & 10/11/15
Ferry, 3-20, 10/27/11
Fletcher, 3-25, 12/7/11
Hitchcock, 2-27, 3/7/11
Hudson, 5-13, 10/1/12
Jordan, 6-26, 11/24 & 11/26/13; 7-23, 6/18 & 6/19/14; 7-24, 6/23 & 6/26/14; 8-2, 7/8/14; 8-3, 7/15 & 7/20/14
Kelly, 8-19, 11/20/14, R8-20, 11/25/14
Kirchner, 3-22, 11/11, 13, & 15/11
Maclay & Sunderland, 4-4, 1/25/12
McRoberts, 2-11, 11/25/10 & others of same date
Millard, 6-21, 10/18 & 10/24/13
Noble, 2-9, 11/10/10
Norris, 4-13, 4/5/12 & Hanchett et al of same date
Parks, 4-4, 1/31/12; 4-5, 2/5/12
Pond, 6-13, 7/8 & 7/9/13
Rice (architect), 3-28, 12/28/11
Rust, 4-5, 2/5/12, R2/5/12; 4-20, 5/26/12
Sage, 2-20, 2/27/11
Templin, 3-9, 7/15/11, R3-10, 7/17/11
Thorne, 7-8, 2/23 & 2/26/14
Turner, 3-25, 12/7/11
Voigtmann, 7-18, 5/8 & 5/11/14
Weeks, 2-10, 11/16/10; 2-12, 12/7/10
White, 2-7, 10/30/10, R2-8, 11/1/10; 2-8, 11/4 & 11/7/10; 2-10, 11/22/10; 2-11, 11/25/10; 2-12, 12/1/10; 2-19, 1/16/11, R2-20, 1/27/11; 2-21, 1/31/11; 2-24, 2/10/11; 2-29, 3/16/11, R3/20/11; 3-1, 5/10/11
Science building
Clements, 6-30, 12/30/13; 7-9, 3/5/14; 7/10, 3/10 & 3/11/14
Ferris, 5-32, 2/25/13
Fuller, 6-19, 10/3/13
Gleason, 5-18, 11/14/12
Gore, 7-9, 3/5/14
Hanchett, 7-9, 3/5/14; 7-10, 3/14/14
Science building
Kahn, 7-1, 1/2/14
Kane, 5-35, 3/15/13
Maclaurin, 6-9, 6/7/13
Newcombe, 6-4, 4/22 & 4/24/13
Pillsbury, 6-5, 5/5/13; 6-7, 5/20/13
Student Christian Association building
Proposal for Lane, 3-10, 7/19/11; 9-13, 4/1/15; 10-16, 10/28/15; 10-25, 12/31/15
III. Academic Units and Programs
Architecture Department
Cooley, 7-1, 1/6 & 1/7/14
James, 7-1, 1/7,9,12,14,16/14
Astronomy Department
Gonzalez-Iramain, 10-23, 12/15/15
Hussey, 10-8, 8/31/15
Dutch, Proposal for study of
Hulst, 9-14, 4/10/15
Education Department
Whitney, 6-29, 12/20/13, R6-30, 12/23/13
Engineering Department
General
Bailey, 10-10, 9/10/15
Chapin, 10-7, 8/18/15 (highways)
Cooley, 7-1, 1/2 & 1/3/14 (Services available to the public); 10-11, 9/17/15
Johnston, 8-1, 7/3 & 7/6/14 (Camp Davis)
Stephens, 8-4, 7/28/14
White, 9-20, 5/25/15; 9-22, 6/12/15, R9-23, 6/15/15
Combining literary & engineering courses
Cooley, 3-27, 12/21/11, R3-28, 12/27/11
Sadler, 5-33, 3/4/13
Electrical engineering
Hubbard, 10-8, 8/28/15 (2 letters), & 8/31/15, R10-9, 9/2/15
Parker, 10-8, 8/28/15
Hiring of naval officers to teach steam engineering and ship building
Bryan, 5-3, 7/19/12; 5-4, 7/22 & 7/29/12
Cone, 5-3, 7/16/12
Cooley, 5-3, 7/16/12
Winthrop, 5-3, 7/16/12
Forestry, School of
Pinchot, 1-19, 10/23/09
Garfield, 4-7, 2/19/12, R4-8, 2/22/12
Mulford, 4-9, 3/4/12
Roth, 3-26, 12/12/11
Snyder, 4-17, 5/4/12; 4-20, 5/31/12
Law Department
Bates, 7-1, 1/3 & 1/5/14
Library
Clements, 9-16, 4/24 & 4/26/15
Jenks, 7-2, 1/8 & 1/9/14; 8-24, 12/29 & 12/30/14
Labadie, 3-17, 10/3/11; 3-18, 10/15/11; 3-20, 10/27 & 10/31/11; 3-24, 11/27/11; 4-1,1/2/12, R4-2, 1/9/12; 4-8, 2/22/12; 5-6, 8/10/12; 5-8, 8/24/12; 5-12, 9/24 & 9/30/12 (re:donation of his collection to library); 6-10, 6/11/13; 6-25, 11/16 & 11/28/13; 7-18, 5/12 & 5/13/14; 7-21, /2 & 6/3/14
Worcester, 8-4, 7/28/14 (re: collection of Philippine books & mss.)
Military science
Grieves, 2-1a, 7/12/10
Museum of Natural History
Hobbs, 5-30, 2/10/13
Ruthven, 8-7, 8/15/14, R 8-13, 10/2/14
Walker, 3-2, 5/18 & 5/20/11
Political Science Department
Fitzpatrick, 6-2, 10/21/13 (re: training for public service)
IV. Student Life and Campus Social Problems
General
Appleman, 5-17, 11/4 & 11/6/12
Editor, N.Y. Herald, 5-30, 2/13/13
Hull, 5-30, 2/13 & 2/18/13
Jordan, 10-4, 7/28/15
Minority Students at U-M
General
DuBois, 1-30, 4/11/10
Phelps, 2-24, 2/12/11
Schurman, 2-31, 4/5/11, R4/7/11
Zartmann, 6-15, 8/11 & 8/12/13
Chinese students
Wong, 6-30, 12/26/13; 7-3, 1/15 & 1/19/14
Hindu students
Bhutia, 5-2, 7/8 & 7/11/12
Comfort, 4-20, 5/28 & 5/29/12)
Roy, 6-24, 11/14 & 11/21/13
Chinese student conference
Chang, 5-12, 9/26/12; 5-13, 10/5 & 10/7/12
Chiu, 5-1, 7/9/12, R5-2, 7/11/12; 5-3, 7/17/12
Effinger, 5-1, 7/9 & 7/11/12
Sam Hoe Kee, 5-8, 8/27/12
Living arrangements and conditions
Jordan, 10-4, 7/28/15
Schepeler, 8-16, 10/26 & 10/28/14
Tucker, 10-16, 10/28/15, R10-17, 11/4/15
IV. Student Life and Campus Social Problems (cont.)
Religion
Barkley, 8-12, 9/22 & 9/23/14
Green, 4-8, 2/26/12, R2/29/12
Kane, 3-25, 12/6/11
Kelsey, 1-29, 3/24/10 (2 items); 1-30, 4/2/10
Lane, 3-26, 12/14/11
Sharpe, 3-23, 11/22/11
Smith, 3-26, 12/12/11
Snyder, 9-19, 5/20/15, R9-20, 5/24/15
Starbuck, 4-1, 1/4/12
Student government
Dyon, 2-31, 4/4/11, R4/6/11
Young, 3-27, 12/22/11, R3-28, 12/26/11
Use of alcohol by students
See entries under V, Social issues of the time.
V. Social and political issues of the time
Child labor
Lovejoy, 5-26, 1/8/13
Cigarette use
Combs, 5-21, 12/4 & 12/6/12
Cummings, 9-5, 2/3 & 2/11/15
Gaston, 12-13, 12/9/10, R12/13/10; 6-5, 5/1/13
Johnson, 8-21, 12/7/14, R8-22, 12/10/14
May, 9-4, 1/28/15
Mead, 4-19, 5/7/12, R5/20/12
Tracy, 8-24, 12/27 & 12/29/14
Tripp, 10-6, 8/14/15, R10-7, 8/18/15
Peace movements (including World Court proposal)
Cadwalader, 6-28, 12/13/13, R6-29, 12/15/13; 6-29, 12/18/13; 9-21, 6/1/15
Ford, 10-8, 8/25/15; 10-9, 9/9 & 9/10/15 (Ford Peace Mission to Europe)
Frers, 10-22, 12/9/15
Grant 10-21, 12/1 & 12/3/15 (Peace Mission)
Hammond, 9-14, 4/12/15, R9-15, 4/29/15 (World Court Congress)
Lochner, 9-6, 2/10/15; 10-16, 10/30/15, R10-17, 11/2/15; 10-20, 11/29/15 (Peace Mission)
Parker, 10-21, 12/6/15, R10-24, 12/22/15
Parsons, 10-8, 8/28 & 8/30/15; 10-9, 9/8/15; 10-13, 10/6/15
Reeves, 9-16, 4/24/15
Short, 7-4, 1/26/14; 7-6, 2/12/14; 7-15, 4/15/14; 12-4, 7/28/15; 10-4, 7/28/15
Wishart, 10-8, 8/24 & 8/25/15; 10-10, 9/10/15; 10-15, 10/21/15
Wood, 9-20, 5/27/15
Philippine independence
Quezon, 4-12, 3/29/12,R4-13, 4/5/12
Race relations
Franklin, 2-35, 5/2/11, R3-3, 5/31/11; 3-4, 6/1/11
Robbins, 6-30, 12/24 & 12/26/13; 7-1, 1/2 & 1/5/14
Ratification of League of Nations treaty
Hunsberger, 3-22, 11/10/11
Simplified spelling
Ferris, 8-12, 10/27/14
Shoop, 7-19, 5/18/14
Vaile, 7-10, 3/12 & 3/13/14, R7-12, 3/31/14; 7-13, 4/2/14, R7-14, 7/10/14
Use of alcohol, on campus and in saloons
Black, 2-29, 3/20/11
Burke, 5-19, 11/15/12
Editor, Detroit Free Press, 5-14, 10/25/12
Edmonds, 3-12, 8/12/11, R3-13, 9/26/11
Foote, 5-21, 12/3 & 12/6/12
Hanchett, 5-20, 11/27/12
Hill, 2-29, 3/17/11
Hobson, 5-26, 1/9/13
Hudson, 4-7, 2/21/12, R4-8, 2/23/12
Humphrey, 5-26, 1/8 & 1/13/13; 8-6, 8/14 & 8/16/14; 8-, 9/28/14
Use of alcohol, on campus and in saloons
MacKenzie, 8-17, 11/3/14
McMurdy, 2-1d, 8/13/10, R2-5, 10/13/10; 2-6, 10/17/10, R10/19/10
Morrow, 2-25, 2/16/11; 2-32, 4/14/11; 3-2, 5/18/11; 3-17, 10/4/11
Prohibition Film Co., 9-21, 6/4/15
Publicity Library, 2-7, 10/26/10
Reed, 5-21, 12/5 & 12/9/12
Rood, 5-2, 7/11/12, R5-3, 7/17 & 7/18/12; 9-24, 6/25/15
Rowden, 7-4, 1/27 & 1/28/14; 9-8, 2/25 & 2/27/15
Rowland, 2-1c, 7/26/10, R7/28/10
Russell, 3-13, 8/18/11
Souter, 3-22, 11/13/11
Warriner, 10-12, 9/25 & 9/28/15
Wright, 1-29, 3/24/10, R1-30, 4/5/10
Women's suffrage
Barbour, 1-29, 3/21/10; 1-30, 4/8 & 4/11/10
Blauveldt, 4-3, 1/16/11
Catt, 2-9, 11/12/10
Howland, 2-10, 11/21/10
Stevens, 1-29, 3/31/10; 1-30, 4/4/10; 2-9, 11/16/10
Trimble, 9-6, 2/13/15, R9-7, 2/17/15
Wilcox, 5-13, 10/3 & 10/7/12, re: refusal to allow Jane Addams to speak in university building
"Letters Written by Men of Note Which are to be Found in the Hutchins Papers"
Selective Subject Card Catalog to the Harry Burns Hutchins papers
The catalog identifies the archival materials within the collecton that correspond to the subjects listed in the catalog cards. The Selective Subject Card Catalog includes entries on the following subjects:
Blacks in Michigan
B'nai B'irth Hillel Foundation, University of Michigan
Election of 1912
Election of 1914
Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940
Hillsdale, Mich.
Indians
Jews in Michigan
Ku Klux Klan (1915- )
Philippine Islands
Prohibition
Radicalism (Social and political)
Spanish-American War
Temperance
University of Michigan Chinese Students Club
University of Michigan Department of Astronomy
University of Michigan Department of Classical Studies
University of Michigan Department of Physics
University of Michigan Faculty
University of Michigan Fraternities
University of Michigan Football
University of Michigan Foreign Students
University of Michigan Hazing
University of Michigan Library
University of Michigan Museum
University of Michigan Reserve Officer Training
University of Michigan School of Music
Western Intercollegiate Conference
Woman Suffrage
Partial Index to Correspondents
This index lists many of the most significant authors or recipients of letters found in the chronologically arranged Correspondence and Other Papers series. The alphabetical listing cites letters by the author by date.
Adams, Charles Kendall, 1835-1902.
1898, July 2, 1910
Adams, Henry Carter, 1851-1921.
Jan. 11, 1898, Feb. 28, 1898, June 20, 1898, 1910, 1911, May 3, 1913, Aug. 18, 1913, Sept. 15, 1913, Oct. 7, 1913 March 2, 1914, Apr. 7, 1914, June 14, 1914, July 17, 1914, Aug. 16, 1914, Feb. 15, 1915, Feb. 23, 1915, March 17, 1915, March 29, 1915, Aug. 23, 1918, Aug. 26, 1918, Sept. 4, 1918, Feb. 4, 1920
American Neutral Conference Committee
Aug. 3, 1916
American Protective Tariff League
Jan. 3, 1912, Jan. 4, 1912, Oct. 9, 1912, Dec. 5, 1912, Nov. 22, 1913, Dec. 31, 1914, Apr. 6, 1916
American Union Against Militarism
July 26, 1916
Angell, Alexis Caswell, 1857-1932.
June 25, 1898, Aug. 6, 1901, Feb. 27, 1911
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
Aug. 23, 1904, March 9, 1910, Oct. 27, 1910, Aug. 9, 1911, Oct. 21, 1914, Nov. 22, 1915
Angell, James Rowland, 1869 1949.
Aug. 6, 1901, 1910, March 16, 1912, Apr. 4, 1912, Apr. 7, 1912, Dec. 10, 1912, June 11, 1913, July 9, 1914, Jan. 9, 1915, June 21, 1916, Jan. 25, 1918, March 20, 1919, March 24, 1919
Ant-Saloon League of Michigan